// import shuffleArray from "../helpers/shuffleArray.js";
// import { getRandomItem } from "../helpers/shuffleAnswer.js";

export const MarvelQuestions = [
  {
    question: "Who plays Tony Stark/Iron Man in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Chris Evans",
      "Robert Downey Jr.",
      "Chris Hemsworth",
      "Mark Ruffalo",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Robert Downey Jr.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Thor's hammer?",
    options: ["Mjolnir", "Stormbreaker", "Gungnir", "Hofund"],
    correctAnswer: "Mjolnir",
  },
  {
    question: "Which infinity stone was located in Loki's scepter?",
    options: ["Space Stone", "Reality Stone", "Mind Stone", "Time Stone"],
    correctAnswer: "Mind Stone",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the fictional metal that makes up Captain America's shield?",
    options: ["Adamantium", "Vibranium", "Uru", "Carbonadium"],
    correctAnswer: "Vibranium",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the main villain in 'Avengers: Infinity War' and 'Avengers: Endgame'?",
    options: ["Loki", "Ultron", "Thanos", "Red Skull"],
    correctAnswer: "Thanos",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the group of intergalactic misfits led by Peter Quill?",
    options: [
      "The Avengers",
      "The Defenders",
      "The Guardians of the Galaxy",
      "The X-Men",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Guardians of the Galaxy",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which actor plays Doctor Strange in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Benedict Cumberbatch",
      "Tom Hiddleston",
      "Martin Freeman",
      "Chiwetel Ejiofor",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Benedict Cumberbatch",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of Tony Stark's AI assistant in the early Iron Man movies?",
    options: ["Friday", "Karen", "Jarvis", "Ultron"],
    correctAnswer: "Jarvis",
  },
  {
    question: "Who plays Black Widow in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Scarlett Johansson",
      "Elizabeth Olsen",
      "Brie Larson",
      "Zoe Saldana",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Scarlett Johansson",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the fictional African country where Black Panther is from?",
    options: ["Zamunda", "Wakanda", "Latveria", "Genosha"],
    correctAnswer: "Wakanda",
  },
  {
    question: "Who directed 'Avengers: Infinity War' and 'Avengers: Endgame'?",
    options: ["Joss Whedon", "Jon Favreau", "The Russo Brothers", "James Gunn"],
    correctAnswer: "The Russo Brothers",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of Peter Parker's love interest in the MCU Spider-Man movies?",
    options: [
      "Gwen Stacy",
      "Mary Jane Watson",
      "Michelle Jones",
      "Felicia Hardy",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Michelle Jones",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which actor plays Bruce Banner/Hulk in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: ["Edward Norton", "Mark Ruffalo", "Eric Bana", "Lou Ferrigno"],
    correctAnswer: "Mark Ruffalo",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Thor's home world?",
    options: ["Vanaheim", "Jotunheim", "Asgard", "Midgard"],
    correctAnswer: "Asgard",
  },
  {
    question: "Who plays Captain America in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: ["Chris Pratt", "Chris Evans", "Chris Hemsworth", "Chris Pine"],
    correctAnswer: "Chris Evans",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the organization that Nick Fury leads?",
    options: ["HYDRA", "SHIELD", "AIM", "SWORD"],
    correctAnswer: "SHIELD",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which character sacrifices themselves to obtain the Soul Stone in 'Avengers: Endgame'?",
    options: ["Black Widow", "Hawkeye", "Gamora", "Iron Man"],
    correctAnswer: "Black Widow",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the AI system that replaces JARVIS in the later Iron Man movies?",
    options: ["Karen", "Edith", "Friday", "Vision"],
    correctAnswer: "Friday",
  },
  {
    question: "Who plays Loki in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Tom Hiddleston",
      "Chris Hemsworth",
      "Benedict Cumberbatch",
      "Tom Holland",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Tom Hiddleston",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the prison planet in 'Thor: Ragnarok'?",
    options: ["Xandar", "Sakaar", "Knowhere", "Vormir"],
    correctAnswer: "Sakaar",
  },
  {
    question: "Which actor plays Star-Lord in 'Guardians of the Galaxy'?",
    options: ["Chris Pratt", "Chris Evans", "Chris Hemsworth", "Chris Pine"],
    correctAnswer: "Chris Pratt",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the villain in 'Black Panther'?",
    options: ["Killmonger", "Klaw", "M'Baku", "W'Kabi"],
    correctAnswer: "Killmonger",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who plays Carol Danvers/Captain Marvel in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Scarlett Johansson",
      "Brie Larson",
      "Elizabeth Olsen",
      "Zoe Saldana",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Brie Larson",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the reality-bending TV show in 'WandaVision'?",
    options: [
      "WandaVision",
      "The Scarlet Witch Show",
      "Westview",
      "The Vision Project",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "WandaVision",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which character says the famous line 'I am Iron Man' in 'Avengers: Endgame'?",
    options: ["Tony Stark", "Peter Parker", "Steve Rogers", "Thanos"],
    correctAnswer: "Tony Stark",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the alien race that invades Earth in 'The Avengers'?",
    options: ["Kree", "Skrulls", "Chitauri", "Frost Giants"],
    correctAnswer: "Chitauri",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who plays Wanda Maximoff/Scarlet Witch in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Elizabeth Olsen",
      "Scarlett Johansson",
      "Brie Larson",
      "Zoe Saldana",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Elizabeth Olsen",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the fictional metal that makes up Wolverine's claws in the X-Men movies?",
    options: ["Vibranium", "Adamantium", "Uru", "Carbonadium"],
    correctAnswer: "Adamantium",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who plays T'Challa/Black Panther in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Michael B. Jordan",
      "Chadwick Boseman",
      "Daniel Kaluuya",
      "John Boyega",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Chadwick Boseman",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the organization that opposes SHIELD in 'Captain America: The Winter Soldier'?",
    options: ["AIM", "HYDRA", "The Ten Rings", "The Hand"],
    correctAnswer: "HYDRA",
  },
  {
    question: "Which character is known as the 'God of Mischief'?",
    options: ["Thor", "Odin", "Loki", "Hela"],
    correctAnswer: "Loki",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the AI system created by Tony Stark that becomes the main villain in 'Avengers: Age of Ultron'?",
    options: ["Jarvis", "Friday", "Ultron", "Vision"],
    correctAnswer: "Ultron",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who plays Natasha Romanoff/Black Widow in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Scarlett Johansson",
      "Elizabeth Olsen",
      "Brie Larson",
      "Zoe Saldana",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Scarlett Johansson",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the magical artifact used by Doctor Strange?",
    options: [
      "Eye of Agamotto",
      "Orb of Agamotto",
      "Wand of Watoomb",
      "Cloak of Levitation",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Eye of Agamotto",
  },
  {
    question: "Which actor plays Ant-Man in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Paul Rudd",
      "Michael Douglas",
      "Evangeline Lilly",
      "Michael Pe√±a",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Paul Rudd",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of Thor's axe in 'Avengers: Infinity War' and 'Avengers: Endgame'?",
    options: ["Mjolnir", "Stormbreaker", "Jarnbjorn", "Thunderstrike"],
    correctAnswer: "Stormbreaker",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who plays Peter Parker/Spider-Man in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Andrew Garfield",
      "Tobey Maguire",
      "Tom Holland",
      "Miles Morales",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Tom Holland",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the planet where the Soul Stone is located?",
    options: ["Titan", "Vormir", "Ego", "Xandar"],
    correctAnswer: "Vormir",
  },
  {
    question: "Which character says 'We have a Hulk' in 'The Avengers'?",
    options: ["Nick Fury", "Tony Stark", "Steve Rogers", "Loki"],
    correctAnswer: "Tony Stark",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the group of enhanced individuals that Wanda and Pietro Maximoff belong to in 'Avengers: Age of Ultron'?",
    options: ["The Inhumans", "The Mutants", "The Enhanced", "The Gifted"],
    correctAnswer: "The Enhanced",
  },
  {
    question: "Who plays Gamora in the 'Guardians of the Galaxy' movies?",
    options: [
      "Zoe Saldana",
      "Karen Gillan",
      "Pom Klementieff",
      "Elizabeth Debicki",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Zoe Saldana",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the fictional country ruled by Doctor Doom in the Marvel comics?",
    options: ["Wakanda", "Sokovia", "Latveria", "Genosha"],
    correctAnswer: "Latveria",
  },
  {
    question: "Who plays Vision in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: [
      "Paul Bettany",
      "James Spader",
      "Aaron Taylor-Johnson",
      "Tom Hiddleston",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Paul Bettany",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the space station that serves as a hub for the  Nova Corps in 'Guardians of the Galaxy'?",
    options: ["Knowhere", "Xandar", "The Kyln", "Ego"],
    correctAnswer: "Xandar",
  },
  {
    question: "Which actor plays Hawkeye in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    options: ["Jeremy Renner", "Mark Ruffalo", "Chris Evans", "Paul Rudd"],
    correctAnswer: "Jeremy Renner",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the all-seeing guardian of Asgard?",
    options: ["Odin", "Heimdall", "Valkyrie", "Sif"],
    correctAnswer: "Heimdall",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who plays Nebula in the 'Guardians of the Galaxy' and 'Avengers' movies?",
    options: [
      "Zoe Saldana",
      "Karen Gillan",
      "Pom Klementieff",
      "Elizabeth Debicki",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Karen Gillan",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the quantum realm expert in the 'Ant-Man' movies?",
    options: ["Hank Pym", "Scott Lang", "Janet van Dyne", "Hope van Dyne"],
    correctAnswer: "Hank Pym",
  },
  {
    question: "Which character is known as the 'Master of the Mystic Arts'?",
    options: ["Iron Man", "Thor", "Doctor Strange", "Scarlet Witch"],
    correctAnswer: "Doctor Strange",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the AI system that helps Peter Parker in his Spider-Man suit?",
    options: ["Friday", "Karen", "Edith", "Jarvis"],
    correctAnswer: "Karen",
  },
];

export default MarvelQuestions;
